oh that was really really nice I'd like
to get Stanley ahead me hey jump bunk
towards the end of the morning we all
get tired your butt gets tired so I
thought we'd have some fun and instead
of keep talking about negative emotions
just depressing why don't we go to the
review of the alarm room which is a
little more cheerful and then we'll come
back to depression at the end of the
class okay so I'm going to do some more
of the review of the last eight years of
Lamia because those of you who decide to
get your master's degree in long room
you're gonna need this okay those of you
who don't decide to become a long room
teacher it's still useful right before
you're teaching okay that's a HCI
teacher so we're on Tim we're on item 81
number 81 and you probably have it it's
a it's a glass flower yeah in 81
what page what page number page ain't
okay okay I'm gonna start explaining it
and then the kids in the tech table will
figure it out
okay so it's a glass flower maybe
someone gave you one in your life
they're very beautiful they're hard to
keep clean right
they always get dusty and they break
easily
okay they break very easily so what it
means is we've been talking about the
long rim as a teaching we didn't reach
the long rim really was just talking
about the introduction to long rim and
what it means is I like to call it your
spiritual real estate okay your mind
okay your mind is very very precious
okay your body is precious but not as
precious as your mind okay you will
switch bodies you will change bodies but
the mind you carry all the time you will
carry it to the next life you carried it
from the past life and those of you who
did three-year retreat it's something
interesting I used to dream about the
Starbucks all the time I don't know like
how dream I'm in Starbucks having a good
coffee in some kind of nice what he call
it biscotti and that was a pretty common
dream during three-year retreat and the
first six months are are quite difficult
you know it's very difficult to adjust
to staying in one room and it's it's not
easy and we were in a different part of
this desert we were over those mountains
we were in a different more empty place
this place no one ever has been no one's
ever lived there and it was wild the
place was there were very strange
animals you know like there's one that
looks like a lobster and when you
meditate they used to crawl up on you
you know and they look just like a
lobster you know and not scorpion not
this big but this big and then there's a
called a Sun spider they're like this
big
and they like they also like meditators
and stuff like that one day we had we
had a lot of rattlesnakes we had five
rattlesnakes inside the fence at the
same time and I got on the fence to to
push one out and then I realized there's
one below me and I had to stay on the
fence for like half an hour and it was
crazy but after six months of quiet you
can talk to animals and it's very cool
so people never stop talking for six
months unless they're at Diamond
Mountain for a three-year retreat and if
you stop talking for six months animals
start to trust you because they don't
talk they don't talk with their mouth
but they talk with their small very tiny
movements of their head or you know but
if you're quiet for six months you can
start to understand them so we had lots
of cool animals we had a wolf that came
every night a coyote every night he came
inside the fence and and then we had pet
rabbits that became very close friend
they come every morning for cookie and
they bang on the door with their
shoulder little rabbit hey I want a
cookie you know then you get a cookie
one day I was so I didn't have a toilet
I didn't have electricity I didn't have
water and so I have to poop outside I
have to try you know those bombing
planes they have to try to drop the bomb
in the correct place so I had a plastic
bag and I have to try to drop the bomb
in the correct place and then I will
trade the bag for my food
it's an Ingo Ingo cause-and-effect and I
remember one day I'm pooping on my bag
outside because it's better to keep your
poop outside and that's great I'm gonna
use that and the rabbit came and hit my
leg you know I stopped busy you know
don't ask for cookie now you know I'm
busy
and she's he keeps hitting my leg and
I'm like what cuz I don't talk I just go
and then he dug a hole right next to
them he wanted me to watch digging a
hole I'm like he's like then then he
spread his legs over the hole and gave
two babies and put them in the hole and
I'm like oh your girl and then she take
grass and put it over the babies
hide them and then she will run away for
about five days because she's bleeding
and the coyote can smell so to protect
the children the mother rabbit will
always run away for one week something
and they will just kind of sit there and
grow a little bit then one day I'm
pooping and from the hole comes to poop
two ears and what's interesting about
rabbit is the ears don't grow they are
full size when they are born so the ear
as as big as the rabbit so two big ears
come out dennis more havoc you know and
they started running around
and I wrote a book about it I didn't
publish it because after a while you
start to suspect there are little
Buddhas you know they are teaching you
things you know and I'll try to publish
it sometime
any anyway why did I talk about that I
forgot completely oh yeah in the after
six months you get really bored and you
can't meditate all day forget it it
sounds nice
three-year retreat sounds very romantic
it's not and it's hot and you know it
was very hot and when we did yoga
you could hear took the water dripping
and but we found out something cool
during meditation you can watch movies
that you saw before we figure out when
you go deeper in your mind that
everything you ever saw in your life is
recorded every conversation you ever had
in every movie you ever saw and every
song you ever heard those impressions
are there I think that's why older
people start to get for forgetful
because the hard drive is for okay I
told John Brady there's a test for
Alzheimer's he said what I said if you
can't remember what Alzheimer's means
you have it so he's like you can sit and
watch a movie okay which why am I
talking about that and what's it have to
do with the glass flower everything you
hear in your life is recorded in your
mind okay everything have everything you
hear and it takes up part of your mind
it you have a limited harddrive you
you can't towards the end of your life
it gets full okay I guess it's wipe
erased when you die okay a lot of it is
erased when you die then you start over
again but what you learn in a three-year
retreat is be careful what you listen to
be careful what you listen to
okay like when you have a choice about
which teaching to go to be picky okay
cuz you know yesterday I said you don't
have time you know right jelsa I mean
when I met you you were 25 I was 25
something like that
then it's like boom you're 65 and you're
like whoa what happened that's one
problem time goes like and time goes
faster as you get older and then but the
other thing is everything is recorded
everything you listen to is recorded so
in the lamrim at the beginning when
they're making the sales pitch for the
lamrim they say choose your teachings
wisely you know choose your teachings
wisely okay don't go to every teaching
available okay because it will be in
your hard drive it will fill up space in
your hard drive okay
and it will stay with you not for one
life for many lives okay for many many
lives okay so when you go to hear some I
don't know dumb New Age psychology last
year's popular thing okay Hiawatha there
was a big snowstorm in flexpa I was
working at the Barnes and Nobles these
two people came in and they got stuck in
the snowstorm
I found them a place to stay and they
were so grateful and they said we got a
car full of ayahuasca you want some and
I said
I made a mistake what's that hakima a
hakama he come on I thought they were
talking about jicama I said yeah I make
salads all the time and they're like so
high Alaska is a drunk it's a plant
which is a drug that hippies are using
for you know instead of studying lamium
you just take a drug it's easier and
it's called higher rasca and then it's
popular right now and then jicama is
it's like a carrot or something it's
good in a salad
I thought they're tight I said y'all
take some and then I said this is not
how I Ross good they said I said wait
you said hey come on oh it's no it's not
jicama why am I talking about that don't
go to everything you hear about okay
somebody says let's go to higher Oscar
thing and then say look my hard drive is
getting pretty full and I'm not sure I
want jicama in my mind for the next
thousand years okay because it's gonna
be in your mind those seeds those
impressions will be in your mind for a
thousand years so when you hear about a
teaching or you hear about some Lama or
you have a chance to go to some high
Alaska thing okay ask yourself do I want
this in my mind for a thousand years
okay
your mind is very it records everything
that's why you can watch movies in
three-year retreat okay so be careful
what you listen to you cannot listen to
anything lightly everything you hear
will stay in your mind okay and it will
affect your mind for many years we say
thousand years okay it will stay there
for a thousand years so do you really
want to watch youtube video about the
cat's jumping you know do you want cats
jumping in your mind you want Jen long
Suns
the oh
do you want these guys shooting people
in your mind for the next thousand you
you know do you really want that in your
mind okay
so your real estate I call it your real
estate this space here is very expensive
and it's very sensitive and it will
record everything so be careful what you
expose your mind to okay be picky you
know check out teaching before you go
and talk to people who've been there and
don't just go cause your friend is going
right young right word
younggu what is that yeah it means
means to run right it means young
means run after teachers because
somebody said it was cool okay
they look handsome or they look
beautiful they look mysterious and be
careful what you open your mind to okay
all right that's the item number 81
your mind is like a glass flower your
mind is very beautiful and your mind is
very fragile and be careful what you be
careful like who you let in your mind
who you let come into your mind be
careful okay you don't have space for
many people and whatever they kind of
teach you is gonna be there for a
thousand years so be careful okay what
that applies to what you watch on the
internet things like that okay
do you really want that in your mind for
a thousand years okay all right item 82
I'm gonna stop in 15 minutes okay ten
fifteen will take a long PP bring maybe
even a son nevermind okay
intimating - it's a pet peeve of mine
Masha my favorite one of my favorite
irritations okay and I saw so in Arizona
I grew up in Arizona we will move to
where I was born in Los Angeles I came
here when I was six years old and if you
live in Arizona you need a car okay
right Velma
by the way llama Palmas here she started
the three jewels in New York thirty
years ago and and that's where we taught
the first a CI question I'd like to
thank her
and she has many good qualities but one
she doesn't have which is how to drive a
car and we tried we tried but she hit so
many cactuses and all the rabbits wrote
me a letter and said this one shouldn't
drive okay then you know my friends who
do drive cuz you have to drive in
Arizona you can't go anywhere
it's the the places are too long so you
have we'd learned to drive when we're 15
in this school the school teaches us
driving and then some of my friends will
say aha I found a good deal I'm like wow
you know they say I got a cheap tires I
found some cheap tires they're really
good you know they're all old and worn
out but they're like $15 you know I'm
gonna save
I'm gonna save like $50 you know I'm I'm
so happy you know and I'm like you live
in Arizona right yeah so that's why you
drive right
yeah because things are so far apart
it's two hours to get to Tucson to to a
real grocery store you know and they're
like yeah so I said what's the speed
limit on highway 10 here 75 miles an
hour how many kilometers per hour 136
and 110 it's a lot of kilometers per
hour it's hundred come on yeah 110 okay
it's fast it's really fast okay and if
the tire blows out you're dead okay
that's in Arizona if you drive a car you
have to drive on the highway you have to
drive a hundred kilometers per hour if
the tire breaks you die understand so
question for you who
save the $50 nobody they're gone they're
dead
I'm like are you crazy buy some new
tires yeah but I want to say $50 I'm
like who's gonna have the $50 me but
you're gonna die because the tire blew
out yeah you have like it's crazy don't
do that okay why are we talking about
that one you look at your phone for five
minutes driving I had a friend of mine
did it a friend from my high school he
was looking at his phone and he was
driving and he hit a car and the other
person had their child standing in the
front seat and the child went through
the window and landed on my friend's
right in front of my friend's car dead
bleeding and dead and he his mind broke
for his whole life he was a good student
he was a good person he was one of the
highest students in the school and he
just became crazy for what for a text
for five minute text you see you do a
small thing and it changes your whole
life understand what am I talking about
going to some stupid Hiawatha teaching
okay some hippie teaching you know last
year someone discovered a new meditation
that Buddha didn't think up someone's
going to teach on Stine about relativity
and you understand that in five minutes
you can plant a seed in your mind that's
taste for a thousand years okay in
fighting it's a car accident going to
Ohio Oscar ceremony something like that
I don't want to pick on hi Oscar
any stupid new meditation things
somebody thought up it's a car accident
and it will change your life for the
rest of your life
you see it's looking at your cell phone
at 75 miles an hour it's a bad tire it's
gonna kill you okay don't think you can
sit
in a foolish teaching and it won't
affect you it will stay in your mind for
a thousand years
okay like a car accident my mother my
stepmother she when my father died when
I was about twenty something three and
she never married and she never dated
much and then then she was on a cruise
you know like long shots trying to get
me to do long shots trying to get us to
take a boat together to Antarctica with
five hundred people on it and spent two
weeks with the Penguins and dual-arm
room I'm not sure about it I agreed but
I didn't give a date so anyway she met a
man a Japanese man on a boat and she
thought well that would be nice to have
a husband and someone I can be with us I
get older you know that would be nice
and she they got married and it and then
it turned out he was not what she
thought you see he wasn't very he
watched TV all day all day and a very
unhappy person you know and and it was
difficult for her and then finally after
five years or something she found out
when he was young he worked for Price
Waterhouse very famous accounting firm
yeah wasn't him Laura valiente's son
just got a they're very big company and
then he had a car accident and he killed
somebody and it broke his mind you see
for his whole life
it broke his mind so you go to a
teaching be careful what you open your
mind to okay be careful it will stay
whatever you're here will stay okay
movies are the same okay be careful what
movies you go to my partner Veronica she
will often walk out of a movie
and it's kind of difficult for me
because I'm like should I walk out or
not you know sometimes I stay okay
that's the 82 okay big mistake biggest
mistake you can make don't think that
going to a teaching which is not which
you haven't checked it out carefully is
just for fun because whatever you open
your mind to it will stay there for many
lifetimes okay many lifetimes five
minutes of doing something without
thinking much like looking at your phone
can ruin your whole life you see what I
mean okay all right everything you hear
is recorded okay all right number 83
there were some people you know like in
the monastery you hear
monks gachet's candidates younger che
gonna be go chase they will say I don't
I don't want to go to alarm em their
special Lamas come and they teach no
Miriam it's not part of the gifted
course okay in the Gashi course you only
get along mmm when you have a visiting
teacher okay it's not part of the
schedule okay
and so the Geshe candidates will say you
know I'm not gonna go to alarm room
that's for that's for the guys who can't
do the guessing course okay and this is
some kind of they put down the alarm
room okay and then pop uncle Rinpoche
got really irritated about it and he
said look if you don't have the three
principal paths okay if you don't have
baby llama in your mind you cannot
succeed in Buddhism you it doesn't
matter you're guessing if you don't have
lar mem in your mind you won't succeed
okay you won't be able to practice
advanced diamond way okay you won't be
able to you need lahrman predominant way
okay Kumar
it's the engine that drives the car okay
la même is the engine which drives the
car you need it okay we all need it and
it's and when you get to Tantra the
second 18 courses which normally takes
about seven years to teach somebody okay
and you teach other people don't
you're not allowed as a a CI teacher or
is any kind of Buddhist teacher you're
not allowed to teach the second eighteen
courses unless they have the first
dating courses okay got it
oh they have 15 I'll just teach him
number three okay they need 18 and then
they do number one got it
and the first three tented courses are
Laurium okay so we're in this system in
your lineage so copy and write we are
following the rules the ancient rules
okay you cannot study diamond way and
tell you do a big long room so that's
gonna be know for most people be a year
an extra year oh gosh la I came to all
the long memory trees I don't need the
first three tented courses I don't care
you have to do it again my teacher had a
car accident it hurt his voice box a
little bit and he talks just like Star
Wars
he'll say what's a guess la I did like
eight years of la Marie with lucky
Michael I don't need the first three
tons of quizzes
yes shut up I don't care you're gonna do
them anyway understand I don't care
alright so why are we doing this LOM
room if we have to do another load room
later because maybe you want to be
specialized in Lerman or maybe you just
want to get enlightened
okay some lower motivation alright okay
nm 84 this is tricky
this item is tricky it's gonna be a
little difficult for you to give me a
good answer when you see it okay so
listen up this is the last thing I'll
teach there we'll take a break who
invented the long room so so if you talk
to people and you say when did lahrman
start and they'll say oh it started a
thousand years ago in Tibet you know ah
tisha got a job from his teacher right
surgery who's name is Naimah rakshita
and tamil archita it's like when
Rinpoche sent me to New York he said
start a business started diamond
business make a million dollars and
here's the diamond cutter Sutra good
luck
but optishot got what ya so sages text
which is awesome text when people hear
sages text when the translators heard
Sergi text they all want to quit their
text and do suggesting so it's called
crown of knives
it's called low Joan right it's a how to
open your heart and after we started his
text we realized that because it's a
lecture by a high Lama we realized it
had a lot of tantor in it and then I was
like I don't know if I should translate
this publicly but we decided to go ahead
with it because that Lama decided it was
okay to mention tundra inside of alum
room okay it's inside of another toxin
anyway so if you ask people who started
the long room they'll say when Dharma
rakshita sent his student ah tisha to
Tibet to teach that's when the alarm
started and and
what was the name of our tee shots
little omnium yeah uh what
yeah body butter butter Deepika yeah
lamp on the path to enlightenment okay
and it's a baby llama it's a tiny lump
and it's a beautiful aluminum someday we
should we should learn it okay so people
will say lahrman started there and
bullcrap Jake gets upset he says no
don't say that
who started the long room and in there
say Lord Buddha okay Lord Buddha started
the Longmen and for $100
okay I gotta make it a little difficult
why does the name of the alarm improve
it must have been taught by the Buddha
well raise your hand I'm not giving away
money to anyone who shouts raise are you
sure okay
I should get a kickback but if you don't
get it right but okay
why what's first of all what's the name
of this of what we're studying yeah good
steps on the path okay then
nice it means somebody knows systems
perfect okay if a monkey hits a
typewriter all day one word will come up
just kidding yeah perfect answer yeah it
the name is of Lamia
is steps to Buddhahood one two three
four five okay who's gonna write that
but okay got it
duh like Papa gets get really upset you
know people said who studied the Lamia
he says such a stupid question you know
who started the path to
buddhahood get it you know understand
okay so if somebody asks you who's
teaching is the lar Miriam here's the
answer in the item it says what the
Buddhists own it's the heel
it's his he taught it because it's the
steps of the path to enlightenment like
how to get to Tucson you got to talk to
somebody who's been to Tucson got it
who wrote the map to Tucson someone who
went to do something duh
okay got it so no debates about who
started the mom room okay now why does
it say deep in one the way he got $100
I'll risk another hundred why does it
say deep in one well slow down good
which is which
yeah deepest teachings on emptiness and
why this teachings on love compassion
okay got it
a hundred dollars he's got to no wait no
he's got a hundred he's gonna hundred
yeah yeah I guess okay that's gotta give
him 50 cuz only more okay alright so
there's two great lineages inside the
lamb rim if you say it simply okay to
put it simply they are called
deep and wide deep and wide which is in
Buddhism describes the ocean the ocean
is called
deep and wide so Buddhism is compared to
the ocean okay we often compare Buddhism
to the ocean so there's two great men
ages deep goes down to the bottom of the
Marianas Trench I don't know eight miles
or something and then why'd you know it
takes time to fly from China to
California right
the ocean is wide okay wide means
teachings on love teachings on
compassion deep means teachings on
emptiness and those are specific
lineages they started with specific
people they were passed on by the
specific people and whilst we'll talk
about that tomorrow okay we'll talk
about there's two great flows of
teaching into the Lamia and there's two
great other flows that are kind of
hidden for $100 clothes we okay I'll
teach you American idiom March are you
ready close but no cigar I think it
refers to some ancient game where if you
win you get a cigar to smoke I don't
know but close means your answer is
partly correct but you didn't win the
prize close but no cigar you didn't want
a cigar denier I know two other ninjas
you got bodhichitta you got emptiness
what's the other two to our understood
you should pay me huh he already said
that what no okay in the lamrim
tradition there's two other practices
yeah I'm thanking you
which means the lineage of personal
practice the manager personal practice
in a CI it's kind of the meditation
modules the practice modules Tanglin you
know how to meditate you know things
like that
personal six times book okay these are
personal practice so that's considered
in the lamrim
a third lineage a third lineage okay
personal practice lineage and then the
fourth one is easy
secret secret lineage okay so really
there's four four streams are combined
in the alarm room okay let's say it
again
compassion stream emptiness stream then
normally the practice stream in those
paintings is put in the middle there's a
third stack of llamas in the middle of
the long room paintings so sits on
copies left you have wisdom because
wisdom is always left hand and then did
some copies right you have compassion
bodhichitta and then in the middle you
have another stack of llamas that's the
personal practice lineage and then you
have okay questions we have about 15
minutes any questions no questions I
have a question for you
what's the three ways to become the most
popular ACI teacher number one know your
material well number two learn your
students names Kichler failed already
number three let them go early sometimes
wait retina has a question okay she has
a microphone actually so
that's tough I'm still gonna write a
book for him about that okay okay cool
mm-hmm that's true
good this comes from an explanation of
Nagarjuna by Johnny nama that we had in
venerable Obama's text and it questions
all of our ideas in life it it's it
shows that everything we think works
doesn't work ok everything not just
atoms but light switches in car keys and
and things like that so because we grew
up with car keys and light switches it's
extremely difficult to break that way of
thinking you know the light why did the
light go on Oh llama pelmet turned the
switch why did the car start oh I I
turned the key you see I mean and it's
it's built into us and it's completely
mistaken okay so and until we understand
it we won't really change the light goes
on when you turn the switch because you
gave light to other people in the past
it has nothing to do with the switch
okay I guess are you saying the light
would go on without the switch yes are
you saying the light won't work
sometimes if I do turn the switch yes
okay and in the car key doesn't start
the car
okay guests are you saying sometimes you
can start a car without a key yes I'm
saying that okay okay so are you saying
sometimes you have a key in the car
doesn't start yeah okay so in in in
higher middle way when you turn the key
nothing touches anything else okay it's
not possible okay
the electricity circuit closes the way I
was taught in high school I don't know
how they teach it now I suspect is the
same
a little balls tennis balls in the wire
copper wire
they this atom hits this atom hits this
annum hits this enemies just and then
charge comes out the other end of the
wire you see so the atoms like a
billiard ball pool ball so this atom his
this atom and then that had him hit stun
and it has to be like that right somehow
it has to be like that this you turn the
car key and that moves closes the
circuit the copper has to touch the
copper okay or steel or whatever it is
and then it closes the circuit and then
the balls start hitting each other and
then it pushes power out the end because
the last ball gets pushed out equal to
the force of the first ball according to
Newton's third law something like that
okay so this is how we live and this how
we understand things and really if you
want to get radical it's a deeper
religion it's the mother religion of
this planet you see you can say I'm
Buddhist you can say I'm Muslim you can
say I'm Christian you can see I'm Jewish
but really we're all atomists we're all
self owners you see and the deeply held
belief of this world is that stuff is
made of stuff you see it's a deeply held
belief and as long as we believe that we
will suffer okay so guests are you know
go back to the atom and I had trouble
teaching it and I felt it when I was in
New York you know I just got it from a
translation that we did the week before
and I said oh this is gonna impress all
the New Yorkers because they're a little
more sophisticated than everybody and so
I you know tried to teach it and it
didn't go very well and I've you know
how you teach something and you feel
like the audience is still like and you
keep talking and it gets worse and then
they're like
and I've actually improved the
presentation I mean I've tried to
improve the presentation because I
wasn't satisfied with it either
so we in where were we we started using
tennis balls in Taiwan Shenzhen in
Shanghai we started like a month ago I
started to use tennis balls so I get
some tennis balls and I bring them up on
the stage and it helps to understand you
know it doesn't solve the problem but it
helps you know so I said this ball hits
this ball and it's electricity going
through the wire right which is why you
could do a WeChat electricity goes two
balls hit balls and then your wiecek
goes to the other person okay so you
can't use balls of ceramic porcelain
clay it won't carry electricity you see
dirt doesn't carry electricity by the
way the best carrier of electricity is
diamond but it's too expensive to make
wires so only if it's copper which is
inexpensive and carries electricity
carries current well the balls hit the
balls easily and the balls get pushed
easily and and that's more efficient
silver is much better than copper but
it's too expensive Gold is also good but
you can't string gold wires all over the
country people will tear them down which
happens in India with the copper ores
but anyway so this ball hits that ball
it has to be a in the metal group of the
periodic chart of the elements it has to
be a metal basically or diamond to carry
electricity well it has to be it has to
be a metal it has to have a certain
number of electrons protons and neutrons
okay and those you know in the model
which is just a model it's not necessary
the way it is those are arranged in
shelves around the core of the atom okay
so it's the core of the atom and then
there's shells of electrons and protons
and then it has a charge the point is
the structure of the tennis ball has to
be exactly that or it's not copper
anymore you see I mean if you pull out a
hydrogen atom sorry yeah if you pull a
hydrogen atom out of water it becomes
something else you see it changes to
helium and oxygen it doesn't work
anymore okay so if you take anything out
of the shell
it's not gonna be copper anymore and it
won't carry electricity so it has to be
that many electrons and that many
protons in the model in the model of
therms right now so those electrons
individually and the protons
individually are generic
an electron in one atom is the same as
an electron in another on them an
electron in a shell of oxygen it's the
same as the electron in a cell in a
shell of copper okay those those are not
different those are just positive
negative charges whatever you see it I
mean if you could take an electron out
of a copper atom and you could take an
electron out of a oxygen atom they're
the same they they're not different
copper electrons are totally the same as
oxygen electrons they're not different
okay it's how you mix them together that
makes it copper or oxygen okay got it
which means if you only make contact
with not one electron okay in a copper
atom it's not gonna work because it's
the same as touching one electron in an
oxygen atom you see it I mean if you can
only make contact with the outer shell
has a single electron in it that
electron is not different from an oxygen
or electron they they are generic all
atoms pieces are the same it's the
arrangement of the pieces that makes
them work okay now does that electron is
it substantial does it have a left side
and a right side can you split an
electron yeah you can that's what that's
what colliders are for you know that's
what that why they make $10,000,000,000
CERN in Switzerland Switzerland that's
why they make these things okay they
break electrons up okay which means
electrons have width and that electron
has a right side okay got it in my okay
so far now when two copper atoms meet
okay you turn the switch right Pamela
turns the switch and then the light goes
on it's supposed to be that tennis-balls
copper atoms hit the next one hit the
next one and then the charge came out of
the into the tungsten of the light okay
supposed to be like that that assumes
that there's a left side on the right
side to the copper atom with me you
still with me okay if if the tennis ball
pushes the tennis other tennis ball if
the whole first tennis ball touches the
whole second tennis ball then there's no
movement because they're in the same
space got it if Stanley hugs Allison let
me make sure this is gonna work and he
tried if he tried to make every inch of
his skin touch every inch of her skin
the only way is if they were standing in
the same space you see it I mean that's
the only way you can check it out now
they can hug is their way to hug each
other that you touch everywhere at the
same time only if you're in the same
spot you see I mean what that means is
stay with me okay this is a terrible
thing to do at the end of the class
I got what that means is if all the
copper atom made contact with all the
next copper atom there would be no
movement of electricity because it would
all be in the same space as if Allison
was touching every inch of Stanley that
means they'd have to be in the same body
that's the only way for all their skin
to make contact with all their skin got
it okay so it must be therefore that
only a part of this tennis ball the
front part touches the Beagle of the
next tennis ball
what Spiegel bottom the ass I mean a
polite word is bottom okay guys that's
not very polite okay so the front side
of this tennis ball has to hit the ass
of the next tennis ball okay the front
end of this ball can't hit the front end
of that ball cuz then there won't be any
movement you see I mean therefore not
all of this ball can touch all of this
ball because Stanley can't hug all of
Ellison in at the same moment you got it
therefore only some of the parts of the
atom only some of the electrons in some
of the shells can make contact with some
of the shells some of the electrons in
the next atom shell got it the front
sight only has certain electrons in that
shell this the next atom of copper only
has electrons some electrons on the back
and some electrons in the front right it
has to be like that because they have
width because you can split them in a
Collider therefore not all of the first
atom of copper is working to touch the
second atom of copper if all the
elements if all the electrons in the
first animal copper are not involved it
cannot be copper and it cannot carry
electricity it's impossible what's
happening when you turn the lights it's
not possible don't say it's weird or
say it's I'm what I'm saying is to think
that the light goes on because she turns
the switch is profound misunderstanding
of the world profound to think that your
husband will stop yelling if you talk to
him it's profound misunderstanding of
the world got it okay and and it's too
big to talk about a thing at 11:01 okay
but everything you think about what
makes anything happen is completely
false
okay completely false
okay it's not that part of Stephen
Hawking is wrong all of Stephen Hawking
is wrong so her husband I told you this
the husband's a publisher he asked me
what's my next book I said I'm gonna
prove Stephen Hawking's wrong then he
got he was feeling conflicted because he
published his Stephen Hawking's okay
let's continue later okay okay I promise
a question from Norbert first thing in
the evening okay yeah
froggen abend okay good
would you lead the Mandela ruk you want
to try you just say sushi
you say what you do okay I'll teach you
the trick in this is how an American
gets to agasshi course you go
Sachi and then the second part you go
okay okay got it
she enjoys she met our time Rishi and
egg and birdie Sangay Schinder made a
bogey no Kaena cherry pie
he done got her Nehemiah DK Lok sanam is
she thought so Sheen surname Yeshe
nature
Kunie top I cool thank you for working
so hard